org.hibernate.internal.SessionFactoryImpl
http://grepcode.com/file/repo1.maven.org/maven2/org.hibernate/hibernate-core/4.3.7.Final/org/hibernate/internal/SessionFactoryImpl.java/

Concrete implementation of the SessionFactory interface. Has the following responsibilities

    caches configuration settings (immutably)
    caches "compiled" mappings ie. EntityPersisters and CollectionPersisters (immutable)
    caches "compiled" queries (memory sensitive cache)
    manages PreparedStatements
    delegates JDBC Connection management to the ConnectionProvider
    factory for instances of SessionImpl 

This class must appear immutable to clients, even if it does all kinds of caching and pooling under the covers. 
It is crucial that the class is not only thread safe, but also highly concurrent. Synchronization must be used extremely sparingly. 

=============================================================================================
=============================================================================================

=============================================================================================


Spring Persistence  with  Hibernate   

 The purpose of dependency injection is to 
decouple the work of resolving external software components from your application business logic. 
Without dependency injection, the details of how a component accesses required services can get 
muddled in with the component’s code. This not only increases the potential for errors, adds code bloat, 
and magnifies maintenance complexities; it couples components together more closely, making it 
difficult to modify dependencies when refactoring or testing.  

Spring is a lightweight IoC container, meaning that it will assume the responsibility of wiring your application dependencies. 
Spring effortlessly ties components together in a loosely coupled manner.

allows code to be more easily refactored and maintained
using Spring’s dependency injection to wire in a key 
framework ensures the integration is done in a decoupled way.

Service facade methods typically group together multiple DAO methods to accomplish business logic as 
a single unit of work. This is the concept of a transaction: the entire method (and all of its side effects) 
completes 100 percent successfully, or the application is rolled back to the state before the method was 
called.


=============================================================================================

Understanding Aspect Oriented Programming (AOP) 
The service layer is where Spring’s AOP support is best utilized. Spring ships with transactional support 
that can be applied to application code through the use of interceptors that enhance your service layer 
code, by weaving in the transactional goodness. An interceptor is code that can be mixed into the 
execution flow of a method, usually delegating to the interceptor before and/or after a particular method 
is invoked. Simply speaking, an interceptor encapsulates the behavior of an aspect at a point in a 
method’s execution. 
It’s not enough to specify that a method should be transactional. You shouldn’t just force each 
method to occur within the confines of a transaction, rolling back if an error occurs and committing if all 
goes well. Perhaps certain methods don’t attempt to modify any data, and therefore should execute 
within the context of a read-only transaction. Or more likely, perhaps some exceptions will trigger a 
rollback, while others will allow the transaction to carry on.  
Pointcuts are another important component of Spring AOP. They help to define where a particular 
aspect (modularized functionality that can be weaved into application logic, such as transactional 
behavior) should be weaved. With Spring’s transactional support, you have fine-grained control over 
which exceptions may trigger a commit or rollback, as well as the details over the transaction itself, such 
as determining the isolation level and whether a method should trigger a new transaction or a nested 
transaction, or execute within the existing transaction.  
At a basic level, Spring accomplishes AOP through the use of the proxy design pattern. When you 
advise your classes by injecting cross-cutting behavior into various methods, you’re not actually 
injecting code throughout your application (although in a way, that is the net effect of using AOP). 
Rather, you’re requesting that Spring create a new proxy class, in which functionality is delegated to your 
existing class along with the transactional implementation (or whatever aspect you are trying to weave 
into your code). This explanation is an oversimplification of what actually happens under the hood, but 
the important thing to remember is that when you weave cross-cutting behavior into your classes via 
AOP, Spring is not directly inserting code; rather, it is replacing your classes with proxies that contain 
your existing code intertwined with the transactional code. Under the hood, this is implemented using 
JDK dynamic proxies or CGLIB bytecode enhancement.

=============================================================================================

The Template pattern is one of the most frequently used idioms within Spring’s ORM framework 
integration packages. Spring provides templates for each of the most popular persistence frameworks, 
making it easy to port your code to a different persistence implementation. The Template Pattern is also 
used by the Spring framework to more effectively integrate JMS, define transactional behavior, and 
provide outbound email message capability, among other things. 
The Template pattern allows a template to be defined in which a series of standard steps are 
followed, delegating to a subclass for those operations that are specific to the business logic.

Typically, a template is defined as an abstract class. To specify the operations to be wrapped within 
the templated workflow, we extend the template class, providing or extending the implementations for 
the abstract methods defined in the template parent class.  
The Template pattern does exactly what its name implies: it extracts boilerplate and redundant 
tasks into a template, delegating to your specific implementation for functionality that can’t be 
templated. In most cases, the code that cannot go in a template is your persistence logic itself. Using the 
Template pattern means you can focus on the database operations, without needing to worry about some of these mundane details: 
•   Opening a database connection 
•   Beginning a transaction 
•   Wrapping your SQL operations in try-catch blocks (to handle unexpected exceptions) 
•   Committing or rolling back a transaction 
•   Closing the database connection (and handling any exceptions during this process) 
•   Catching any exceptions that might occur in the transaction

Although the HibernateTemplate and JpaTemplate provide an effective construct for streamlining
persistence operations, they are no longer as necessary as they once were. Hibernate 3 shipped with a
feature called Contextual Sessions, which provides greater flexibility around the scope of a Session. Part
of what Spring’s ORM support provides is the facilitation of a conversation surrounding persistence
behavior, allowing Hibernate and JPA operations to be seamlessly integrated into Spring’s transactional
support. Spring’s transactional features couldn’t be properly utilized if every Hibernate operation
created a new Session and a new database connection. To tie multiple lower-level persistence
operations into a holistic “conversation,” Spring uses the capabilities of ThreadLocal, allowing disparate
operations to be scoped across a continuous thread. Recent versions of Hibernate provide a pluggable
mechanism for defining how accessing the current Session should work. This new capability makes the
HibernateTemplate and JpaTemplate a bit redundant in some circumstances. 

=============================================================================================

With an IoC container at its core, Spring helps to reduce application complexity, as well as coupling 
between classes, by handling the details necessary to integrate one dependency with another. Spring 
also provides transactional behavior, AOP capability, and infrastructural classes for numerous 
persistence frameworks, such as Hibernate and JPA. 
Hibernate is an ORM framework intended to translate between relational databases and the realm 
of object-oriented development. Hibernate provides a querying interface, using Hibernate Query 
Language (HQL) or the Hibernate Criteria API. Together, Spring and Hibernate are a dynamic duo, 
capable of simplifying dependency collaboration, reducing coupling, and providing abstractions over 
persistence operations. 
JPA is a Java standard for persistence, the design of which was significantly influenced by the 
Hibernate developers. Hibernate can be used as an implementation provider for JPA, allowing you to 
adhere to standards and gain framework portability, while still utilizing the excellent Hibernate 
implementation. However, there are some useful features that are not available in JPA, but are present 
only in the Hibernate implementation. With the release of JPA 2.0, many of the limitations of the JPA 
spec have been addressed, bringing more parity to Hibernate and JPA. For instance, JPA 2.0 now 
provides a Criteria API for querying in an object-oriented manner, and compile-time checking.  


=============================================================================================
The Application Context 
Spring’s job is to parse your configuration files and then instantiate your managed classes, resolving 
their interdependencies. Spring is often called a container, since it is designed to create and manage all 
the dependencies within your application, serving as a foundation and context through which beans 
may also be looked up. This core engine is represented by a base interface called BeanFactory.  
The BeanFactory interface defines the core Spring engine that conglomerates your beans and wires 
the collaborating dependencies together. 

The ApplicationContext extends the BeanFactory interface, providing a set of more robust features. 
The separation can come in handy if you are building a very lightweight application and don’t need 
some of these more advanced features. But for most applications (especially server-side software), you 
will want to use an ApplicationContext implementation. In the case of web applications, you will use a 
WebApplicationContext. Spring ships with a listener that you can throw into your web.xml file to 
automatically bootstrap the Spring ApplicationContext and load your configuration file. It’s as easy as 
adding the following lines into your web.xml: 
 
<listener> 
    <listener-class> 
        org.springframework.web.context.request.RequestContextListener 
    </listener-class> 
</listener> 
 These lines will ensure that Spring is loaded when your application first starts up and will parse the 
configuration file located at WEB-INF/applicationcontext.xml. 
If you’re not building a web application, it’s just as easy to load the Spring container. In this case, we 
recommend going with the ClassPathXmlApplicationContext implementation, which is designed to load 
the Spring configuration files from the classpath. It is invoked in the following way: 
 
ApplicationContext context =  
    new ClassPathXmlApplicationContext(new String[]{"configfile1.xml", "configfile2.xml"}); 
 
You can see just how easy it is to get a Spring container instantiated. Once you have a reference to 
the ApplicationContext, you can use it however you wish. The reference that is returned to you is the 
loaded ApplicationContext, with all the beans that you defined instantiated and dependencies resolved. 
If you felt so inclined, you could access a bean by name, simply by invoking the following: 
 
UsefulClass usefulClass =  (UsefulClass) context.getBean("myBeanName"); 
 
Assuming that your bean is defined somewhere in your Spring configuration files (referenced by the 
ID or name attribute), Spring will hand you your class instance, ready to go (meaning all of its 
dependencies will have been injected). However, we strongly recommend that you try to avoid issuing 
calls to getBean().  
The whole point of Spring is automatic dependency injection, which means not looking up your 
beans when you need them. That’s dependency lookup, which is so 1995. While this approach does 
decouple and defer your class dependencies, it still requires an explicit lookup step. As a rule of thumb, if 
you need a reference to a particular dependency, specify these details in the configuration, not in your 
code.  
Some developers will rely on getBean() only in circumstances in which they always need a new 
instance of their class (each time they make the call). A better solution to this problem is using the 
lookup-method property in your XML configuration. This property coerces Spring to override or 
implement the specified method with code that will always return a new instance of a designated bean. 
An alternate strategy for accessing beans from the ApplicationContext is to implement the 
ApplicationContextAware interface. This interface has the following method: 
 
void setApplicationContext(ApplicationContext context); 
 With access to Spring’s ApplicationContext, your class has the flexibility to look up beans by name 
or type, without you needing to write code to acquire an ApplicationContext from the classpath directly. 
In practice, there shouldn’t be many cases where you need to integrate Spring’s API so deeply into your 
code. The more common approach is to let Spring manage the relationships between beans dynamically 
through dependency injection. 
=============================================================================================
Dependency Injection and Inversion of Control 
Enterprise applications are composed of many objects that provide behavior to emulate business
processes. Two very important design patterns have emerged to manage the relationships between
objects in an object-oriented application: 
Dependency injection (DI): Classes that employ dependency injection specify
the objects that they interact with through constructor arguments, factory
method parameters, or public mutators (aka setters). With a dependency-
injection container or framework like Spring, the ability to externalize simple
class properties is just the beginning. Developers can create a complex tree of
dependencies, leaving the work of figuring out how each dependency is created
and set (also called injected or wired) to the Spring lightweight container.  
Inversion of Control (IoC): When object location or instantiation is removed as a
responsibility for a given bean and instead left to the framework, control has
been inverted. This inversion of control is a very powerful concept and
represents the foundation on which the Spring Framework is based. 
  
Dependency injection and IoC lead you down a path toward clean code that embodies high 
cohesion and loose coupling. 
=============================================================================================
 every object that you configure for use in the 
Spring container is registered in the ApplicationContext, which is a subinterface of Spring’s BeanFactory. 
The ApplicationContext provides you with the tools you need to interact with your configured beans. 
We recommend creating a root configuration file, and then importing all other configuration files, so 
that the XML files don’t become too large and obtuse. 


Component Scanning 
The next important piece of configuration is component scanning, which was introduced in Spring 2.5 
as a mechanism for further simplifying the way you go about configuring Spring applications. 
 
<context:component-scan base-package="com.prospringhibernate"> 
 
This declaration will cause Spring to locate every @Component, @Repository, and @Service in your 
application. In practical terms, this allows you to write a POJO, and then simply annotate the new POJO 
as a @Service. Spring will then automatically detect, instantiate, and dependency inject your service at 
startup time.  
Additionally, component scanning turns on other notable Spring annotations like @Inject, @Named, 
and @PostConstruct support. These annotations allow you to use common Spring and Java EE 
annotations in your classes without needing to do any special configuration. The most commonly used 
annotation is @Inject, which instructs Spring to dependency-inject an object into your class. You can 
then also have your new service injected into any other class that requires it, simply by declaring a field 
for your service inside the relying class. 
■ Note @Inject and @Named are just two of the annotations defined as a part of JSR-330. JSR-330 defines a 
standard set of annotations to be used in Java EE applications. @Inject and @Named are wholesale replacements 
for the @Autowired and @Qualifier annotations in Spring that you may already be familiar with. This makes your 
application more portable in the event that you should decide to change your dependency-injection implementation 
to something like Google Guice. 
=============================================================================================
JNDI is often described as the opposite of Spring’s IoC. Instead of having dependencies 
automatically injected into your application, JNDI allows dependencies to be looked up from a centrally 
managed directory. There are certainly benefits to both approaches. For example, in the case of JNDI, 
developers can define logical names for database resources in their application configuration, but allow 
a system administrator to manage mapping that logical name to the proper database connection pool in 
the web application container configurations, effectively deferring the specification of database 
connection details until runtime. When a database migration is required, JNDI can simplify some of 
these administrative tasks, as no changes to the application configuration will be required.

 The FactoryBean is Spring’s 
answer to the well-known factory design pattern. The key concept here is that you remove a direct 
dependency on a specific implementation by delaying the selection or instantiation of the specific 
implementation until runtime. You define a factory, and it is the factory’s job to pick the correct 
implementation at runtime and instantiate (or look up) that specific class. 
The Spring FactoryBean concept is quite similar. Normally in Spring, when you define a bean, the 
class specified by the classname attribute is the class that will be instantiated and injected into other 
beans that have that bean ID wired into them. This isn’t the case with a FactoryBean. When you use a 
FactoryBean, you are instead instantiating a factory class that will then be responsible for creating the 
specific implementation used to resolve dependencies in Spring. So essentially, the classname attribute 
in this case just defines a factory implementation, whose job will then be to create the actual target 
implementation you need.  
This concept  allows us to use multiple strategies to access a datasource without tying ourselves 
down to a particular solution. I
=============================================================================================

=============================================================================================

=============================================================================================

